Adi Shakti Puja
アディ　シャクティ　プージャ
2004, Cabella Ligure, İtalya
2004年　イタリア　カベッラ　リグーレにて
Today's meeting is very special.
今日の集会は特別です
It's a very, very special day also,
今日は特別な日でもあり
extremely special and very blissful.
多大なお恵みの日です
The reason is, it talks and sings and says
なぜならある力　秩序が
about the born Order
誕生したと歌われ
born Power,
語られるからで
the Original, the Adi, the Primordial.
それはアディであり始源なるものです
And this one is responsible
偉大な宇宙の創造は
for creating this great universe.
この力によります
Why this has started and how it works out is...
理由や方法については
already you know;
あなた方は既に知っています
I need not talk about that.
わざわざ話す必要はありません
But today we have to talk about this Power,
今日はこの力について話します
which is hidden in your hearts,
あなたのハートに隠されています
by which you can do whatever you like to create
それによりあなたは創造できます
a new world, a new family,  a new standards,
新しい世界や家族や秩序
everything that is not known so far.
まだ見ぬ全てを創造できます
That is quite possible;
それは可能です
that is quite possible and is being done,
それは可能であり起こりつつあります
but what is difficult is
難しいのは
how to make people more adaptable, more
人間をどう適応させるか
in tune with each other, absolutely.
互いに完全に同調させるか
It seems to be a difficult thing.
それが難しいようです
They're all right among themselves,
彼らは身内では大丈夫です
if they are own friends, their own styles and things.
同じスタイルなどを持つ仲間内なら大丈夫です
But to make them absolutely one, one with each other
別々の者を完全に一つにしようとするのは
in one tune, in one line is very, very difficult
とても難しいし
and it should not be done.
するべきではありません
That's not supposed to be;
一つにするべきではなく
they're not supposed to be like that,
そうされるべきでもなく
but it has to work out.
そうなるべきなのです
Now the problem is,
問題は
we have beautiful people, beautiful souls,
美しい魂の人たちがいるのに
but they do not become
彼らは
so one with each other as they should have.
十分に一つになれないことです
Now, how to solve this problem?
どう解決すれば良いでしょう
Many people have asked Me,
多くの人々が
"Mother, how to make that problem";
「マザーなぜこの問題があるのでしょう」
I just smiled.
私は微笑みました
Because, if you see the original idea
なぜならあなた方が
why we started this x ray
どうしてX線のような
why we started this new kind of a
新しい方法を用いるようになったか
understanding, new kind of penetration -
それを考えると
because we wanted to find out the oneness, the newness
私たちが皆ひとつであり唯一の存在であると
in every person.
分かるためだからです
Now you should be very much thankful that
だから皆の内面が一つであり
you are all one, one inside,
一人として違いがないことに
there's nothing second.
感謝すべきなのです
There's only one and that one when it speaks
その唯一なる存在が輝き
and when it wants to administer something,
何かを執り行うなら
then you'll be amazed that it's all done the same way.
すべてが同じ方法になることに驚くでしょう
It's the same thing and it works out the same way.
同じことには同じ様に作用します
There is no change, there's no difference between the two.
両者に違いはありません
Despite that, despite that, our minds are roving,
にも関わらず私達の心はさ迷い
roving into some sort of a problem,
サハジャヨガには意味のないような
which has no significance in Sahaja Yoga.
問題にはまってしまいます
Now the main problem that we have is that
私達は問題がないということを
we don't realize that we have no problem.
解っていないことが一番の問題です
We are without any problems.
私達には問題がありません
We think that there are problems and
問題があると考え
we should deal with problems,
それに取り組むべきと思いますが
but there are none; none of those problems are there.
そもそも問題がないのです
I don't see any problem anywhere.
私にはどこにも見当たりません
Those who think they have problems,
問題があると思う人は
I've asked them to write it down,
私に手紙を書くように言いました
and I'll try to answer them
私から問題について
and tell them what sort of a problem it is.
教えようと思います
But before I could do anything, I would like to say
でも私がなにか言う前に
that still our Sahaja Yogis are not come to that level
サハジャヨギ達がまだまだ
to understand the oneness, the uniqueness
自らが唯一無二であることを
in their hearts of their oneness.
理解する水準でないと言いたいです
All this comes from within, not from without,
全ては外からでなく内面からなので
so all efforts made outside is of no use.
外面の努力は全て無駄です
We have to be effortless and become what we are.
私達は努力を放棄して自分自身にならねばならない
There you'll find  there is no... nothing.
そこであなたは無を発見するでしょう
There is no need to have another... another meeting or
別の集会も謎解きも
any other coding something,
何も必要ありません
no need; it's all there.
全てはそこにあるのです
Just you have to be that, to become that.
あなたがそうなれば良いだけです
This is rather difficult to understand for people
これを理解するのはかなり難しく
who have different noses, different faces, different everything,
皆が違った鼻をして顔も違いながら
to become the same.
同じになれるのです
But you are, you are; because
でも同じなのです
you don't know that you are that's why you are looking different.
同じだからこそ違って見えるのです
So, I have to tell you one thing:  that you are all One.
みな一つであると言わなければなりません
One in the sense that your everything,
同じというのは
impulse, every feeling,
衝動も感情も理解も全てが
every understanding is the same.
同じだということです
Only thing is that it arises at a wrong time,
ただ違ったタイミングで経験するから
at different times and it gives you a wrong impression
勘違いして違うと感じますが
that it is different, but actually it is not.
実際はそうではありません
It is only one, one relationship,
一つの存在で一つの関係です
and the relationship is with the Adi Shakti
アディシャクティとの関係です
- that you are a part and parcel of Adi Shakti;
あなたはその一部であり
that whatever one may try,
何をしようとするにしても
one cannot get separated from Adi Shakti.
アディシャクティなしには行えません
You are born out of Her and you are guided by Her,
あなたは彼女から生まれ導かれ
you are looked after (by) Her.
養われます
Everything seems to be one to Me
私には全てが一つです
while you people think there is a different
あなたには道も行動も違うと思いますが
line of a course, line of action, which is wrong.
それは間違いです
Whatever I may say, it has to be proved,
私が何を言うにしてもそれは証明されるべきで
otherwise why should you accept such a ghastly statement?
ぞっとする話をあなたは受け入れることはありません
Myself, I am one with you
私自身あなたと一つです
and I am always... will remain the same with all of you.
いつもそうだしこれからもずっと皆さんと一緒です
For Me there is no difference. I don't see anything like that.
私には少しも違いはありません
It's outside; it's only your clothes and your style.
外側のことで服やスタイルだけです
Inside, maybe, what temperament you have,
内面的な気質は
depends on your temperament.
多分人によるでしょう
If that temperament changes a little bit,
それが少し変わるだけで
you will see the oneness among all of you
あなた達は一体感を感じて
and the differences will be lost in no time.
あっという間に違いはなくなるでしょう
Today I saw a very dangerous man.
今日私はとても危険な人に会いました
I thought he can kill Me if he wants.
彼はそうしたければ私を殺せると思いました
He can do whatever he likes. But no, it didn't happen.
何でも出たはずですがそうなりませんでした
Why? Because I never understood him.
なぜなら私が誤解していたのです
He was not like that.  He just wanted to show his respect.
彼は私に敬意を示したかっただけだったのです
He didn't want to kill Me or didn't want to do anything wrong.
私を殺害しようとしたかったわけではないのです
It's very surprising how you understand each other.
あなたがいかに互いを理解するかに驚きます
Unless and until you have proper understanding of each other,
その理解が適切にならない限り
you cannot achieve anything that is sober [Not clear],
ありのままを理解することができません
that is essential, that is right, that is the truth.
本質や正しさや真理が分かりません
So, the truth started long time back,
真理とはずっと前に
much before anybody could think of having a truth here.
人がそれを望むずっと前から存在しましたが
It's all went off with so many things which were not truthful
多くの偽りの物事と共に
and then the truth went away.
真理も失われてしまいました
Like, I would say, that the snake...
例えば私があのヘビは
snake was born out of ignorance
無知からから生まれと言い
that the other snakes started supporting.
他のヘビをがそれを支持すると
Snakes after snakes,  they started growing up
ヘビがどんどん増えて
and filling the whole universe with dishonesty and with wrong ideas
不正や嘘で宇宙全体を一杯にします
and believing in it and started fighting,
するとそれを信じてお互いに
killing each other. But they were all snakes.
殺し合います 皆同じヘビなのにです
So how much one should believe in their nonsense?
どれだけこのナンセンスを信じるのでしょう
How much one should follow their nonsense?
どれだけそれに従うのでしょう
How much anybody should accept their nonsense?
どれほどそれを受け入れるのでしょう
It's very difficult.
とても難しいことです
But it is acceptable much more than the truth.
なのに真理以上に受け入れられています
The truth is not so very easily accepted as the untruth is.
不正は真理より簡単に受け入れられます
Why?
なぜでしょう
- Because we are standing in untruth.
私達が不正に立脚しているからです
Our own understanding is untruth
私達の理解が不正確だからです
and we'll have to change our understanding to truth,
だから真理の理解の仕方を変えなければいけません
which is not difficult because we are truth. We are the truth.
それは難しくありません 私達が真理だからです
To become the truth, which we are, why should it be difficult?
真理になるのは何故難しいのでしょう
Should not, but it happens.
自然に起こることなのに
So that means there is something wrong
何かがおかしいからです
somewhere within us, which we should find out.
私達のどこがおかしいのか
And the thing that isnwrong with us,
何がおかしいのか見つけなさい
within, is that we cannot face ourselves.
自分のどこに向き合えていないかです
We cannot face ourselves.
私たちは自分に向き合えません
We face others, not ourselves.
人には向きますが自分には無理です
We never see ourselves.
自分を見ることはありません
We have no idea as to what our own situation is.
自分の置かれた状況を理解していません
And for that is only you needed a Mother - to show you.
それこそがマザーに示されるべきことです
And that's how the Mother came here
そのためにマザーがここに来たのです
on this earth to tell you what's the problem with you, within.
地上に降りてあなたの内なる問題を 指摘しに来たのです
This one is to be accepted. This principle has to be practised.
それを受け入れなさい この原理を実践しなさい
And you'll be amazed at yourself
するとあなたが知識をもっていて
how much you have already a knowledge
どれほど自分や周囲を理解できるかに
about yourself and about all the surroundings.
自分自身が驚でしょう
There's nothing so special, nothing so extraordinary,
特別でも異質でもないことです
but only thing is you have to be acceptable to yourself.
自分を受け入れるだけでよいのです
I think people are becoming Sahaja Yogis,
人はサハジャヨギになっているようで
but they are not.
なりきっていません
They are not Sahaja Yogis but they are trying to become.
成ろうとしていますがまだ成り切れていません
On the contrary, they should know that they are Sahaja Yogis
反対に彼らは自分がサハジャヨギであると 知るべきです
and they don't have to become anything.
何かになる必要はありません
Then there's no problem.
すると問題がなくなります
But when you have accepted that there is
でも違うサハジャヨガやヨギがあると
Sahaja Yoga different, and Sahaja Yogis are different
受け入れると
and you are different,
あなたが違う存在になります
then how can you become Sahaja Yogis?
するとどうやってサハジャヨギになれるでしょう
The thing is the ignorance, is the ignorance that we have,
無知です 私達の無知ゆえなのです
that we are behaving like strangers towards each other.
まるで知らない人同士のように振る舞う
Complete ignorance. We have to know that we are all,
全くの無知です 全てが同じであると
all the same, very much.
理解する必要があります
There's no need to have any ignorance of any kind.
無知は全く必要ありません
And when that happens, the problems of the whole world
それが起こればたちまちにして
will be solved without any difficulty.
世界の問題がたやすく解決されるでしょう
Today's Puja is a special one
今日のプージャは特別です
because you are doing the Puja of something
なぜならこのプージャは
that never went into any transformation,
決して変わることも変容もせず
which was not changed at all; it was just the same,
常に同じ様に存在し続けるもの
remained the same, born with the same and is still with the same.
そのためのプージャだからです
In such a Puja, what do I have to say?
そこで私が何を言えるでしょう
Why anyone has to say?
なにか言う必要があるでしょうか
Nothing. Just be one with yourself.
ありません 自分自身と一体になりなさい
That's the point we come to
それこそが結論で
- that we have to be one with ourselves,
自己と一体になるのです
and not to get it lost in the words
頭で考えて言葉に溺れたり
or in the atmosphere or in the other... our movements of brain.
雰囲気や他人に流されたりしないことです
Because, this is the time when the brain starts moving;
現代こそ脳が刺激され
and when it starts moving, it loses its control over himself.
コントロールを失う時代だからです
Like a snake - unless and until it is in its own place,
ヘビのようなもので
there's no danger;
然るべき場所に納まるべきです
but as he starts moving, there's a danger to him.
動き出すと危険です
In the same way, we have to know that our mind is
私達の心も同じで
very very difficult and should not go into wrong direction.
すぐに間違った方向に行こうとします
For that, we have to do the Primordial Mother's Puja
そのためには原始の母のプージャが必要です
because we should try to be on the line of Primordial Mother.
私達は原始の母に沿うようになるべきで
We have to keep ourselves Primordial.
自身の始原を保持し
We have to work out our Primordial Self,
本源的な自己を働かせ
and not to change ourselves for any rhyme or reason.
自分を詩歌や理論に流されないことです
This will be the best thing, if we can achieve it.
これができれば最高の達成です
I'm sure we can, not such a problem.
できると確信しています 問題ありません
Only thing is that we are so conscious of being Indians,
ただ私達は自分がインド人であるとか
being English,  being English, European and all that.
英国人とかヨーロッパ人とか意識しすぎています
But we are not.
でも私達は違います
We are just ourselves and that's what we have to achieve
私達は単に私達そのものであり
- that Oneness with ourselves. May God bless you all!
それと一つになることが目標です 神のお恵みがありますように！